# Achu Robi

Watford WD17 2AF achu.robi@yahoo.com +447784861508

With over 8 years of experience in customer support/service, sales and marketing, administration I have developed a solid understanding of market dynamics in varoius industries including Healthcare. I possess in-depth knowledge of creating exceptional customer experiences through effective engagement, positive attitude, and top-tier service. Recognized consistently as a top performer by my team, I have received appreciation from management for delivering excellent service.

My skills include effective organization, strong interpersonal abilities, man management, and diplomacy/public relations. I have demonstrated project implementation skills and thrive under pressure in fast-paced environments, always setting clear goals for each project.

For the past 2 years, I have been working in the UK healthcare industry, where I have held various administrative roles. This experience has further honed my skills and provided me with a comprehensive understanding of the sector's unique demands and challenges.

#### Personal Details

**Driver's License:** Cars

Eligible to work in the UK: Yes

Highest Level of Education: A-Level or equivalent

**Industry:** Administrative Assistance, Automotive, Banking & Finance, Business Operations, Call Centre, Customer Service, Healthcare, Hospitality & Tourism, IT Operations & Helpdesk, Installation & Maintenance, Insurance, Management, Marketing, Media & Communications, Medical Information, Other, Real Estate, Retail, Sales, Technology

Total years of experience: 8

## Work Experience

#### **Patient Services Advisor**

OSD HEALTHCARE-Hemel Hempstead November 2022 to Present

- Ensure that patients' and visitors' enquiries are handled courteously, efficiently and confidentially
- Billing and account management at the front desk.
- Adding charges, preparing quotes/estimates, conducting selfpay transactions at front desk.
- Handling appointment bookings on realtime
- · Alert doctors to urgent concerns or outstanding telephone calls or visits, as appropriate
- Helping in all admin related jobs and data processing under GDPR guidelines.
- Relay test results to patients

- · Ensure that outstanding matters and information are handed over to colleagues at shift change
- Check prescription requests and ensure they are directed to the requested collection point
- Handle patients' positive and negative feedback initially, seeking advice from or referring to Patient Services Supervisor or Assistant Practice Manager as appropriate
- Answer incoming calls in a friendly, polite and professional manner. Consider the request, taking appropriate action or redirecting to other personnel as appropriate.
- Take telephone messages, appointments details and home visit requests accurately and efficiently and enter details on to computer system as appropriate
- CQC, infection control & IT representative from the team
- Signpost patients to the most appropriate service, seeking advice if this is not clear.
- Check own nhs.net email account frequently during shift and ensure that all messages are responded to and actioned promptly and as appropriate
- Check practice generic and reception nhs.net email accounts frequently during shift and ensure that all messages are responded to and actioned promptly and as appropriate
- Send, receive and record facsimile messages
- Be conversant and deal with procedure for new patients wishing to register with the practice
- Be conversant with online Patient Services and Care Navigation and record outcomes as appropriate
- Be responsible for security of the building if last person leaving
- Be conversant with Panic Alarm system and act upon this if necessary
- Attend and participate in team, staff meetings and other meetings as required
- Be fully conversant with patient services procedures and developments
- Ensure that filing, record keeping and distribution of documents and mail are undertaken efficiently and promptly.
- · Assist with sending out of patient recall letters and other similar correspondence
- Ensure that noticeboards are kept up to date and that appropriate literature is displayed.
- Arrange and ensure that adequate supplies are available.
- Contribute to a safe working environment
- Assist with mentoring/training new staff, as directed by Patient Services Supervisor or Assistant Practice Manager
- Any other ad hoc duties as required

#### **Urgent Night Time Administrator**

4Ways Healthcare-Hemel Hempstead February 2022 to October 2022

- Attend telephone vetting calls from NHS trusts for various scans.
- Provide necessary support for the clients to retrieve or provide urgent reports.
- Uploading scan reports using CRIS and Non-Cris systems (via emails too).
- Retrieve necessary clinical informations from CRIS and Non CRIS systems.
- Inform urgent report over the phone to clients.

- Identify and escalate priority issues, only when other options have been exhausted.
- Checking and verifying generated reports for any errors.
- Checking and solving breaching scan reports requests.
- Adhere to customer confidentiality guidance and data protection legislation Work within key targets/ SLAs set by the business.
- Provide sufficient informations on the delayed reports.
- Liaise with internal and trusts IT to solve any IT related issues at out of hours time

## **Customer Service Advisor (Temporary)**

The TJX Companies, Inc.-Watford October 2021 to January 2022

- Provide quality and personalised responses to a wide variety of customer (both internal and external) queries using email, phone and social media channels
- · Assess customer requirements and aim to resolve queries first time whenever possible
- Update and maintain system records, ensuring the relevant information and approval has been provided
- Work within the continuous improvement culture of the business by looking for ways to improve and simplify processes and procedures
- Follow through on and manage all customer contacts (internal and external), resolving issues to an exceptional standard in a timely and efficient manner, recording information and updating key systems as required.
- Make outbound contacts with customers to resolve customer issues
- Perform administrative duties, such as manual processes, data entry to help gain customer insight and improve customer processes
- Deliver all services in accordance with agreed Service Level Agreements
- Understand operational processes and answer FAQ Responsible for own development and support others to maximise potential
- Leave all customers with a good impression of TJX Europe
- Liaise with key internal departments where required to ensure a swift resolution of customer problems.
- Identify and escalate priority issues, only when other options have been exhausted
- Adhere to customer confidentiality guidance and data protection legislation Work within key targets/ SLAs set by the business

#### **Customer Service Representative**

Anglesey Fuels Pvt Ltd (SHELL)-Woodbridge December 2020 to August 2021

- Welcoming and greeting customers.
- Providing great customer satisfaction through excellent service.
- Keeping the station looking great.
- Maintaining a fully stocked store.
- Understanding customers' needs and wants.

- Recommending and displaying items that match customer needs.
- Managing point-of-sale processes.
- Receiving new stock.
- Knowing about our products and sharing that knowledge with customers.
- inventory management, stock checks and back office operations

## **Senior Business Development Officer**

Asia Insurance Review Event Services Pvt Ltd-Technopark, Kerala May 2013 to January 2020

- Supports team manager and performs management duties when manager is absent or out of office.
- Planning Sales and marketing strategy for the events and conferences.
- Day to day follow ups using tele and video means to contact clients.
- Identifying the target audience and preparing leads.
- Conducting day to day meeting with the conference production and marketing teams.
- Provides encouragement to team members, including communicating team goals and identifying areas for new training or skill checks.
- Assists management with hiring processes and new team member training.
- Answers team member questions, helps with team member problems, and oversees team member work for quality and guideline compliance.
- Develops strategies to promote team member adherence to company regulations and performance goals.
- Conducts team meetings to update members on best practices and continuing expectations.
- Generates and shares comprehensive and detailed reports about team performance, mission-related objectives, and deadlines.
- Ensures company brand materials and physical working spaces meet and exceed company presentation standards.
- Provides quality customer service, including interacting with customers, answering customer inquiries, and effectively handling customer complaints.

#### **Customer Service Manager (CSM)**

IYE Services Pvt Ltd-Dubai Internet City June 2017 to July 2018

- Organize, plan, and monitor a company's customer service department to ensure optimized interaction between a company and its clients.
- Oversee the hiring, orienting, and training of an organization's customer experience team.
- Solving escalated complaints and resolving it on a specific time frame.
- Utilize social media platforms in reaching out to customers to help resolve issues and provide quick response to inquiries
- Supervise the activities of customer experience team to ensure their interaction with customers reflect positively on the company

- Developing and implementing strategies useful in improving customer relationship, dedication and satisfactions.
- Define and implement standards/procedures for ensuring optimal customer experience
- · Oversee the hiring, orienting, and training of an organization's customer experience team
- Monitor the activities of the customer service team to ensure compliance with acceptable standards of customer service
- Organize training programs for customer experience representatives in order to update their job knowledge and enhance their skills
- Utilize customer relationship management (CRM) tools in coordinating and monitoring customer experience operations
- Attend seminars, workshops, and conferences to improve on existing job knowledge.

#### **Business Development Executive**

Yarab Technologies Pvt.Ltd-Technopark, Kerala December 2012 to May 2013

- Performing outbound calls with the customers.
- Ensure to meet the daily sales target.
- Resolve customer queries and enhance maximum customer satisfaction.
- Performing as active SME.
- Act on Sales Reports initiated by Supervisor after his review and comments.
- Strategizing & implementing ways to achieve sales targets.
- Send out confirmation letters to clients to confirm sale status and establish contact with the customer.
- Prepare daily / weekly progress report (daily performance tracker).
- Handled the tasks of preparing quotations for various products.
- · Responsible for maintaining files of sales invoice, Performa invoice and purchase orders
- Handled the tasks of promoting products and services of the organization.

## **Project Developer & Branch in Charge**

Plasma Engineering Academy

#### Education

#### course in computer Science

kerala University - Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala May 2008 to April 2012

## A-Level or equivalent in Biology Science

Kerala Higher Secondary education (St Marys Higher Secondary School) - Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala March 2005 to March 2007

#### GCSE or equivalent in Science

Indian Certificate of Secondary Education (Seventh day Adeventist High School, TVM) - Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala

### Skills

- Call Center (5 years)
- Customer Care (6 years)
- CSR
- Customer Service (6 years)
- Customer Support (6 years)
- Telecommunication (4 years)
- Communication skills (10+ years)
- email
- Email marketing (3 years)
- Social media marketing (2 years)
- · Photo editing
- Content creation (5 years)
- Sales administration (5 years)
- Computer skills (9 years)
- Office experience (7 years)
- Bilingual
- SAP CRM (2 years)
- SAP ERP (3 years)
- Salesforce (1 year)
- Email support (3 years)
- Microsoft Office (10+ years)
- Sales (5 years)
- Management
- Business Development
- Microsoft Excel (3 years)
- Adobe Photoshop (2 years)
- Salesforce (2 years)
- Patient service (2 years)
- Medical terminology (2 years)
- healthcare softwares (3 years)
- GP surgery experience (2 years)